<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nicolette Mojica</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nicolette Mojica</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Biography Hi, I’m Nicolette! I’m a native Texan, originally from Houston but enjoying life in Austin. I’m a life-long dancer and a firm believer in the power of music and creative movement. I’m also a biology student at The University of Texas at Austin. Outside of that, I enjoy spending time in nature and going on adventures with my friends. Hook ’em!
 Education The University of Texas at Austin  2016-2019 Biology BSA   Clear Brook High School  2012-2016    Experience Substitute Teacher -2019 - present - Supervised students while their instructer was gone</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects2/</guid>
      <description> Projects Project 1
 Unit I data wrangling and exploratory analysis project  Project 2
 Unit II modeling, inference, and prediction project   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description> Project 1 To conclude Unit I, I created an exploratory data analysis project. This project compared data about every country’s alcohol consumption and the percentage of their GDP spent on health care. Follow the link below to see what I found!
Project 1
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2 - NSM724</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I will be using the same dataset that I created for project 1 with the addition of a population variable. This is a dataset that compares countries’ alcohol consumption and percentage of GDP spent on healthcare, as well as their population. The “liters” variable shows the liters of pure alcohol consumed per capita for each country. The “type” and “servings” variables go together. The servings variable indicates the number of servings of a certain type of alcohol each country drinks per capita and the type variable indicates the type of alcohol that the servings variable is referring to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/blog/project2about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/project2about/</guid>
      <description> Project 2 After learning all about modeling in Unit 2, I created project 2. Project 2 expands on project 1, drawing together alcohol consumption and percentage of GDP spent on health care in every country. This project also looks at the population of each country. See below to learn about my findings.
Project 2
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1 - NSM724</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This project focuses on two datasets named “drinks” and “healthgdp”. “drinks” is a dataset from fivethirtyeight which gives liters and servings of alcohol consumption per capita in every country. “healthgdp” contains data released by the World Health Organization which gives info about the percentage of the yearly GDP that is spent on healthcare in every country. It also assigns each country to a region. I will be joining these datasets and analyzing the data in the hopes of seeing the habits of alcohol consumption in each region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rojects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Project 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Is Fun!</title>
      <link>/blog/pythonblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/pythonblog/</guid>
      <description>This semester I learned a little bit about Python. As a science person, it was cool to use Python to make DNA analysis a little easier. I wrote a small function to count k-mers that I’ve inserted below. It gives you back every possible k-mer, as well as the number of times it appears.
def count_kmers(sequence,k): counts = {} num_kmers = len(sequence) - k + 1 for i in range(num_kmers): kmer = sequence[i:i+k] if kmer not in counts: counts[kmer] = 0 counts[kmer] += 1 return counts Now we can use this function on a sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>